<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Arsh Imtiaz</title>
        <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/</link>
        <description>The personal site for Arsh Imtiaz</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://arshimtiaz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>When Red Teaming Meets Car Hacking: Building a Virtual Vehicle Pentest Lab on My Laptop</title>
    <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/virtual-vehicle-lab/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Arsh Imtiaz</author>
    <guid>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/virtual-vehicle-lab/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
  
  <small>How does one emulate cars at home?</small>
</div>
<p>Every car hacking tool I have come across required expensive ECUs, adapters or even full test benches. Having worked with test cars before, I got an insight into how time consuming and expensive, if not difficult it is to set a working HIL (Hardware-In-Loop) setup.
I didn&rsquo;t want to wait for hardware to understand how automotive networks behave - I wanted to simulate it.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Why Networking Fundamentals Should Be Your First Step</title>
    <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/networking-fundamentals/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Arsh Imtiaz</author>
    <guid>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/networking-fundamentals/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
  
  <small>Networking is fun. Also, it is the part that keeps your hacks from breaking at the worst time.</small>
</div>
<p><big>So, you wanna be a hacker?</big></p>
<p>Cool. I did too. I jumped into Kali, sprayed tools, and followed tutorials like a robot. Things worked, but I could not explain why. That was my first big lesson: <strong>without networking, most of security looks like magic</strong>. No magic here. Just packets, addresses, ports, and paths.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>My First Wi-Fi Pentest</title>
    <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/wifi-hacking/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Arsh Imtiaz</author>
    <guid>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/wifi-hacking/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p></p>
<h1 id="my-first-wi-fi-pentest">My First Wi-Fi Pentest</h1>
<p>There’s a massive difference between watching pentesting videos and actually doing it. This was my first time seriously trying Wi-Fi pentesting, and it was a mix of pure excitement, a bunch of silly mistakes, and that one moment of “YES! It finally worked.”</p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer: This is just my story, not a tutorial. Everything I did was on my own network. Don’t go around trying this on random Wi-Fi unless you like the idea of explaining yourself to law enforcement.</strong></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Docker to Detection: Setting Up Wazuh SIEM for Beginners</title>
    <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/wazuh-setup/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Arsh Imtiaz</author>
    <guid>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/wazuh-setup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p></p>
<p>Setting up a SIEM (Security Information and Event Management) system might sound intimidating if you’re just getting started, but it’s a rewarding project that gives you real insight into how cybersecurity professionals monitor and detect threats. I recently built a Wazuh-based SIEM entirely with Docker and connected my personal Linux workstation as an agent. In this post, I’ll walk you through the process with practical commands for both Arch Linux and Debian users.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Welcome</title>
    <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/welcome/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:59:12 &#43;0300</pubDate>
    <author>Arsh Imtiaz</author>
    <guid>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcome-to-my-blog">Welcome to My Blog</h1>
<p>Hello, and thank you for visiting my blog!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m Arsh Imtiaz — a cybersecurity professional passionate about ethical hacking, information security, and continuous learning in the ever-evolving world of technology.</p>
<h2 id="about-this-blog">About This Blog</h2>
<p>This space is dedicated to sharing insights, experiences, and practical knowledge related to cybersecurity and ethical hacking. Here, you’ll find:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Technical write-ups and tutorials</strong> covering various tools, techniques, and challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Personal reflections</strong> on projects, learning journeys, and industry trends.</li>
<li><strong>CTF walkthroughs and writeups</strong> from platforms like TryHackMe and HackTheBox.</li>
<li>Occasional commentary on broader tech topics, aimed at both beginners and professionals.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="why-i-created-this-blog">Why I Created This Blog</h2>
<p>I launched this blog to document my professional journey, share knowledge with the community, and foster connections with fellow security enthusiasts. Whether you&rsquo;re just starting out or looking to deepen your skills, I hope you find something valuable here.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
