<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Aircrack-Ng - Tag - Arsh Imtiaz</title>
        <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/tags/aircrack-ng/</link>
        <description>Aircrack-Ng - Tag - Arsh Imtiaz</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arshimtiaz.github.io/tags/aircrack-ng/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>My First Wi-Fi Pentest</title>
    <link>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/my-first-wi-fi-pentest/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Arsh Imtiaz</author>
    <guid>https://arshimtiaz.github.io/posts/my-first-wi-fi-pentest/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/wifi-pent.png" title="Wi-Fi Pentesting" data-thumbnail="/images/wifi-pent.png">
        
    </a>
<h1 id="my-first-wi-fi-pentest">My First Wi-Fi Pentest</h1>
<p>There’s a massive difference between watching pentesting videos and actually doing it. This was my first time seriously trying Wi-Fi pentesting, and it was a mix of pure excitement, a bunch of silly mistakes, and that one moment of “YES! It finally worked.”</p>
<p><strong>Disclaimer: This is just my story, not a tutorial. Everything I did was on my own network. Don’t go around trying this on random Wi-Fi unless you like the idea of explaining yourself to law enforcement.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="gearing-up">Gearing Up</h2>
<p>My setup was simple – my Arch Linux laptop, an Alfa adapter, and the Aircrack-ng suite.</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/adapter.png" title="Alfa AWUS036ACS" data-thumbnail="/images/adapter.png" data-sub-html="<h2>My trusty Alfa adapter, aka &ldquo;the antenna that could&rdquo;</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">My trusty Alfa adapter, aka &ldquo;the antenna that could&rdquo;</figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>At this point, I was overconfident. In my head, it was just: “Enable monitor mode, grab handshake, crack password. Done.”</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Spoiler: life doesn’t work that way.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="where-i-fell-flat">Where I Fell Flat</h2>
<p>The very first thing I did? I forgot to disable all the services that fight you for control of the adapter.<br>
Result: Warnings everywhere, services kept messing with monitor mode.</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/airmon-ng.png" title="warnings everywhere" data-thumbnail="/images/airmon-ng.png" data-sub-html="<h2>When your OS says &ldquo;nah&rdquo;</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">When your OS says &ldquo;nah&rdquo;</figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>Once I figured that out, things finally started looking cool. My terminal was scrolling with access points like some cyberpunk movie scene.</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/airodump-ng.png" title="warnings everywhere" data-thumbnail="/images/airodump-ng.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Access point recon (cool hackery stuff)</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Access point recon (cool hackery stuff)</figcaption>
    </figure>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-why-is-nothing-happening-phase">The &ldquo;Why Is Nothing Happening?&rdquo; Phase</h2>
<p>I locked onto my target, sat back, and… nothing. No handshake.</p>
<p>Turns out, distance <em>does</em> matter. I was sitting too far from the router like some wannabe hacker in a corner. Moving closer fixed everything, and that glorious “Handshake captured!” message finally appeared.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-brutal-reality-check">The Brutal Reality Check</h2>
<p>Cracking it? Yeah, that part didn’t happen. My wordlist didn’t have the password (because of course it didn’t). Turns out a <a href="https://github.com/brannondorsey/naive-hashcat/releases/download/data/rockyou.txt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">14 million password wordlist</a> doesn&rsquo;t contain the password from all over the universe. (because of course it doesn&rsquo;t).</p>
<p>But honestly, just getting that handshake felt like a small win. I’d done the whole process myself and figured out where I’d gone wrong.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h2>
<ul>
<li>The tools are just tools. Knowing how to troubleshoot when things fail is the real skill.</li>
<li>Proximity is underrated. Sitting 10 feet further might be the difference between success and nothing happening.</li>
<li>Wordlists are everything. A bad one means hours of wasted time.</li>
<li>There are certainly <em>other methods</em> of &ldquo;getting passwords&rdquo; from your target other than using wordlists *wink* (will cover this in the future)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-im-glad-i-did-it-manually">Why I’m Glad I Did It Manually</h2>
<p>I could’ve just used <a href="https://github.com/v1s1t0r1sh3r3/airgeddon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer "><strong>Airgeddon</strong></a> or some automated script, but figuring it out command by command taught me <em>why</em> things work, not just how to click buttons.</p>
<p>Next up? I’ll see if I can get Airgeddon to make my life easier <em>without</em> making me lazy.</p>
<hr>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/hackerman.gif" title="Hackerman" data-thumbnail="/images/hackerman.gif">
        
    </a>
<p>This wasn’t some cinematic “Hollywood hacking” moment. It was messy, frustrating, and way less glamorous than it looks online. But that’s what made it fun.</p>
<p>The real flex isn’t showing commands – it’s showing that you understand <strong>what’s happening under the hood</strong> and can figure things out when they go wrong.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
